

Marcos Porto

Software Engineer Ruby on Rails | React



About Me

Hello! I'm Marcos 🖖 I'm a software developer with main knowledge in JavaScript and Ruby on Rails. I worked for about 8 years as a Production Engineer in business administration, however, I've been dedicating myself to completing this career transition. As a result, I've reached excellent front-end skills and also in back-end. Finally, I'm a person motivated by new challenges and able to handle multiple daily tasks. I have a strong sense of organization and I use to have a creative approach to problem-solving being able to work autonomously, and quickly grasp new concepts.

33 Age

mrcsporto@gmail.com Email +55 (85) 99752-3466 Whatsapp

Address Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil

Professional Skills

HTML Ruby **Postgres** Git/Github JavaScript

Portfolio

Mass Orders Upload to Batabase

Application to register client orders by upon .csv file.

Ruby

Bank Account Manager

App to simulate the management of a bank account and it's transactions.

Brazilian community about software development, code

Ruby

Inventory Control System

Public REST API to manage products, inventory centers

and orders. Ruby

Ruby

review and discussion.

Forum Web Site

Tic-Tac-Toe Game

Tic-tac-toe multiplayer game

Javascript

See More →

Reporting Control System

Application and also an API for reporting abductions in an apocalypse world.

Ruby

Work Experience

Procurement Buyerat Gocase

Apr 2020 - Nov 2022

I started the purchasing department. From hiring people, standardizing processes, developing KPIs, and also managing OKRs.

Process Engineer at Bosch Portugal

Apr 2019 - Apr 2020

I was responsible to optimize the manufacturing processes, manage production capacity, line balancing and also build dashboards in Power BI.

Operation Manager at Normatel Home Center

Apr 2015 - Dec 2018

I was responsible for managing, teams, processes, policies, KPIs, pricing strategy, inventory, contracts, and registrations. I also managed IT projects with an emphasis on the business model in SAP ERP.

Education

2022 - 2023

Technical Course

Full Stack development

Digital College

Web programming concepts and fundamentals, programming logic and algorithms, Git and Github. Frontend in Javascript, HTML, CCS and React. Backend development in Node.js, Express.js and MySQL. System operation with DevOps, Cloud Infrastructure, and deployment.

2019 - 2020

Master's Degree

Master of Operation Management Porto Business School - University of Porto

Analyze, design, and implement production systems aimed at maximizing value and ensuring they are aligned with the organization's strategy.

2013 - 2018

Bachelor of Production Engineer University of Fortaleza

Bachelor's Degree Design, implement, improve and maintain production systems with a systemic approach in order to deal with integrated systems, equipment, technologies, and products.